ANDY CHEN

Rich experience in full-stack/DLT/DApp software engineering with full product life-cycle and open source contribution. I care about user experience as much as internal/external developer experience, with multiple experiences in working with a cross-functional team. Currently earned <u>AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate</u>(AWS CSAA).

amazingandyyy@gmail.com github.com/amazingandyyy https://amazingandyyy.com linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy

EXPERIENCE

Vechain Community, Open Source— Founder and Project lead May 2018 - PRESENT

- Contributed to vechain/thor, vechain/thorify, and other Vechain open source projects on GitHub.
- Publish multiples code samples of thorify usage and DApp on Vechain Blockchain, tutorials of migrating from Ethereum to Vechain Platform.
- Initiate a Vechain Node Observation app and Vechain Full Node hosting service to the community.

Bodhi, QTUM blockchain, *Software Engineer* May 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Developed and audited production-ready complex solidity smart contracts on QTUM blockchain.
- Reverse engineered metamask and design the architecture of <u>qrypto</u> prototype.
- Migration electron-based Bodhi app to browser-based DApp and ultimately led to an increase in usage by 2 times.
- Built the prototype of qinfura, a full node service for QTUM ecosystem.

<u>Ventured International Inc.</u>, San Francisco — *Chief Product Officer* July 2017 - April 2018 (company resolved)

- Co-authored whitepaper, designed and developed the end-to-end DApp from zero-to-one in less than a month.
- Implemented TDD with Jest to engineer production-ready smart contracts in Solidity and deployed to Ethereum Live Network with Truffle framework.
- Developed an ERC-20 compatible VentureCoin(<u>VCN</u>) token and successfully launched a 3-month <u>crowd-sale</u> in November 2017.

Yeah Education Group, Berkeley — Lead Engineer & CTO Dec. 2015 - April 2017

- Led a cross-timezone development team to migrate the full-stack app from angular 1.6 to React 15 in 3 months and migrate RESTful API to GraphQL hybrid API.
- Successfully scaled the business 20 times to 2M annual revenue in 2016 and led the company to join Berkeley-owned Skydeck incubator and push the company to become UC Berkeley's only official admission partner.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, **Nodejs**, **Golang**, Python, **Solidity**

Full-stack: HTML/SCSS, JS/Node, React/Redux, Webpack, RWD, MERN stack, MEAN 2.0, MongoDB, SQL, Next.js, SSR, SEO, JWT

DevOps: NPM, **Docker/K8S**, **TravisCI**, Truffle, **AWS CSAA**

Blockchain: **Ethereum**, Truffle, web3, **vechainThor**, thorify, **connex**, QTUM, NEO

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Vechain/thorify, update documentation and suggest #8[closed] new thorify features

amazingandyyy/mern-stack, open source my mern stack boilerplate repo and gained 14 forks and participants

nodejs/node, submitted
PR#10092[merged] and
#10093[merged] to update and
improve testing environment

dawsbot/mailto, submitted PR#3[closed], PR#4[merged] to resolve multiple issues and optimize key features

<u>Andysign Studio</u>, Mountain View — *Freelance Software Engineer* Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Coordinated with 8 clients to develop websites including Groove Trend and Swallet, and Taiwanese Volunteer Group with about 1K daily visitors.
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase in traffic and earned a full satisfaction rate from clients.

EDUCATION

<u>Draper University</u>, San Mateo — *Certificated Startup Hero* Sept 2018 - Oct 2018

Grown <u>venode</u> project into <u>BNS</u> and graduated as top 3 of "the most fundable project" voted by hundreds of VCs on Demo Day. Completed full Hero Training Program and was nominated as "the most positive student" by Tim Draper.

<u>University of California, Berkeley</u>, Berkeley — *Bachelor's of Science, Cognitive Science* June 2016 - July 2018

The first and only student completing all 3 blockchain courses (Blockchain for Developers, Blockchain Lab, Blockchain Fundamental).

Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Technology from SCET and served as Tech Chair in Senior Class Council 18. Completed courses included Data Vis., Computer HCI, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math and Machine Learning.

PROJECTS

<u>Leptin</u> — A PoW cryptocurrency implement in Nodejs

Designed and built a whole cryptocurrency in Nodejs with leveraging the power of WebRTC, LevelDB, hyperlogs to build a peer-to-peer blockchain implementing Proof-of-work, secp256k1 and dynamical difficulty.

Etherbrite — An Eventbrite-like DApp.

Built a DApp in Solidity, TruffleJS, Web3js and React/Redux. From deploying events on smart contract to register and check-in.

<u>Py-leptin</u> — A cryptocurrency implement in Python 3

Designed and built a cryptocurrency prototype in Python and exposable RESTFul APIs. Complete features including functional wallets and simple Proof of work.

VRPlayer — A video player built with ReactVR and openGL

Built this video player on the fist of ReactVR's launch, with a focus on the interaction details of user experience in virtual reality.

HACKATHONS/AWARDS

H4YT Blockchain Hackathon 2018 - **No.1 nomination by Cosmos** for building <u>Celadon</u>, a lotionjs middleware donating money to help our environment.

LAUNCH Hackathon 2016 - **1st place of Uber Challenge** for building <u>Teleport</u>, an advertisement site that connects customers and business.

AT&T IoT Hackathon - **Best Mobile App and IoT Solution Overall**[2015] for building

Connect, a radio player

controlled with Myo gesture

controller.

MENTORSHIP/GLOG

Distributed Tech Salon

authored a technical blog sharing a series of tutorials on web development, smart contract, DevOps and software design topics.

<u>Group</u> on Github I founded virtual organization on Github to discuss topics of developer experience and developer tools.

NodeSchool Oakland and San Francisco Chapter Served as regular monthly mentor in Nodeschool Oakland